vitamix.com 2010-01-17

# Welcome to Vitamix - Literature Request Form

Vitamix CORPORATION  
(U.S. and Canada) 

For UK & Ireland Click here

This Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) discloses the privacy practices for Vitamix Corporation (“us” or “we”) with respect to its websites and various related services (collectively, the “Site”). We are committed to protecting your privacy when you visit and use our Site. Please read the information below to learn the following regarding your use of this Site. 

You acknowledge that this Policy is part of our Site Terms of Use, and by accessing or using our Site, you agree to be bound by all of its terms and conditions. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not use this Site.

We reserve the right to change this Policy at any time. Such changes, modifications, additions or deletions shall be effective immediately upon notice thereof, which may be given by means including, but not limited to, issuing an email to the email address listed by registered users and posting the revised Policy on this page. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to maintain a valid email address as a registered user, review this Site and this Policy periodically and to be aware of any modifications. Your continued use of the Site after such modifications will constitute your: (a) acknowledgment of the modified Policy; and (b) agreement to abide and be bound by the modified Policy.

Privacy Policy

**1. _Types of Information Collected._**

The type of information we collect depends on how you use this Site. We collect two types of information about our users: Personally Identifiable Information you provide to us voluntarily and Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

> A. _Personally Identifiable Information_ : refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are. You may voluntarily provide certain Personally Identifiable Information to us when you (a) register with us for an ecommerce store account or register your email address with us; (b) enter sweepstakes or contests sponsored by us; (c) sign up for special offers from select third parties; (d) send email messages or feedback, submit forms or transmit other information by email; (e) submit your credit card or other payment information when ordering and purchasing products and services on our Site; (f) submit or post content in discussion forums or other public areas of our Site; or (g) complete a survey. It is completely optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, we may ask that you provide us personal information, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including zip code), email address, telephone and facsimile numbers, credit card number, and other personal identifying information. Depending upon the activity, some of the information we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity.
> 
> B. _Non-Personally Identifiable Information_ : refers to information that does not by itself identify you as a specific individual. We gather certain non-personally identifiable information about you based upon how you search and shop through our site, including which pages you view and products you order while visiting our Site. For system administration and statistical analysis purposes, this information is compiled and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis. This information may include the Web Site’s Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, which tells us the country and state you are searching our Site from. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. 

**2. _Collection Methods and Use of Information._**

We do not collect any Personally Identifiable Information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us when asked on our Site. You will have the chance to review the information you submit before completing any order, entry form or registration form. We use your Personally Identifiable Information to provide our services to you as required by our agreements with you, to resolve disputes and to enforce our agreements with you, including our Site _Terms of Use_ and this Policy. We will also use your Personally Identifiable Information to provide you with a more efficient and customized educational and shopping experience, process your orders, improve our marketing and promotional efforts, statistically analyze Site use, improve our product and service offerings, and enhance our Site’s content, layout, and services. We may contact you regarding administrative notices and/or send you occasional emails or regular mail regarding our products, services, special offers and upcoming events that may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive this information, please click on the “Unsubscribe” link shown on all our emails and electronic newsletters to you or contact us at the address or telephone number listed below and we will remove your name from our mailing lists.

We also collect, or enlist a third party service provider to collect, store, process and manage certain Non-Personally Identifiable Information. We use your Non-Personally Identifiable Information to diagnose problems with our servers and software, administer our Site, connect you to the correct ecommerce store for your country and gather and analyze demographic and other statistical information. Our third party service providers may also provide us with summary, but not individual, reports that will tell us how our Site is being used. We may also share such aggregate statistical and demographic information with select third parties, such as our advertisers, however, these reports do not contain any Personally Identifiable Information.

**3. _Release of Information._**

We do occasionally sell your name and mailing address (but not your email address) to select companies whose products or services you may find of interest to you, however, we do not sell any other Personally Identifiable Information about you to other third parties. We also provide some of our services through contractual arrangements with affiliates, services providers and other third parties that require us to share your Personal Identifiable Information to them in order to deliver those services. For example, we must release your credit card information to the card-issuing bank to confirm payment for products and services purchased on this Site; release your address information to the delivery service to deliver products that you ordered; and provide order information to third parties that help us provide customer service.

We encourage our service providers to adopt and post privacy policies. However, the use of your Personally Identifiable Information by our service providers is governed by their privacy policies and is not subject to our control.

Occasionally we may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personally Identifiable Information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

**4. _Updating and Correcting Information._**

You may change any of the personal information you have provided to us on this Site by clicking the “Update Profile” link attached to our emails and electronic newsletters, by writing us at: Vitamix Corporation, 8615 Usher Road, Cleveland, Ohio 44138, Attn: Kristi Poltrone or by calling us directly at 1-800-848-2649.

Please include your name, address, and/or email address when you contact us.

We will only keep your Personally Identifiable Information as long as we need it for the reasons it was originally collected from you. When we no longer need your Personally Identifiable Information for our purposes, we will destroy, delete or erase that information or convert it into an anonymous form in accordance with our standard data retention and destruction policies.

You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of past transactions, you cannot delete information associated with past transactions on this Site. In addition, it may be impossible to completely delete your information without some residual information because of backups.

**6. _Security of Information._**

At our Site you can be assured that your Personally Identifiable Information is secure, consistent with current industry standards. The importance of security for all Personally Identifiable Information associated with our customers is of utmost concern to us. Your Personally Identifiable Information is protected in several ways. We encrypt your Personally Identifiable Information and thereby prevent unauthorized parties from viewing such information when it is transmitted to us. In addition, your Personally Identifiable Information resides on servers located in a controlled, secured environment that only authorized personnel have access to.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this Site cannot be guaranteed; and (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party.

**7. _Cookies._**

When you use our Site we will store cookies on your computer in order to facilitate and customize your use of our Site. A cookie is a small data text file, which a Web Site stores on your computer’s hard drive (if your Web browser permits) for record keeping purposes. Our cookies store your ecommerce store user account information, the country where you are located, and your ecommerce store shopping cart selections so you do not have to select items more than once. The cookies make your use of the Site easier, make the Site run more smoothly and help us maintain a secure Site. You are always free to decline our cookies if your Web browser permits, but some parts of our Site may not work properly if you disable our cookies.

We allow third party advertisers to display banner advertisements on our Site. These third party advertisers will place a separate cookie on your computer when you click on their banner. Vitamix does not provide our advertisers with any of your Personally Identifiable Information, however, Vitamix has no access or control over cookies used by such advertisers.

**8. _Links to and Privacy Policies of Third Party Sites._**

This Policy only applies to information collected from this Site by Vitamix. Once you click on a link to another website (“Linked Site”), you are no longer on this Site. This Policy does not apply to the content or privacy practices of any Linked Site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each and every website or Linked Site that collects personally identifiable information. You should contact advertisers, other websites or Linked Sites directly if you have any questions about their privacy policies or their use of the information they collect.

**9. _Miscellaneous Privacy Issues._**

> A. _Age Requirement._ You must be at least 18 years old to have our permission to use this Site. Our policy is that we do not knowingly collect, use or disclose Personally Identifiable Information about visitors that are under 18 years of age.
> 
> B. _Public Postings._ You should also be aware that when Personally Identifiable Information is voluntarily disclosed (i.e. your name, email address, etc.) in the discussion forums or other public areas on this Site, that information, along with any information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and used by third parties and may result in unsolicited messages from third parties. Such activities are beyond our control and this Policy does not apply to such information. Any submissions to chat rooms or other public areas on this Site are accepted with the understanding that they are accessible to all third parties. If you do not want your comments to be viewed by third parties, you are advised not to make any submissions.
> 
> C. _User Registration and Password._ Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password and/or account information. To ensure the effectiveness of your password, we recommend that you do not disclose your user identification or password to anyone. Please be careful and responsible whenever you’re online.

**10. _Business Transfer or Sale._**

Our business is growing. We may buy or sell all or part of our business or the business of a third party. All or part of your personal information may be transferred to a new business or owner as a result of such transactions, however, your personal information will continue to be protected by any pre-existing Privacy Policy of Vitamix Corporation, unless you agree otherwise.

**11. _Contact Information._**

If you have any questions about this Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, please contact us by sending a letter to:

Vitamix Corporation  
8615 Usher Road  
Cleveland, Ohio 44138  
Attn: Customer Service

You may also contact us by email at [service@vitamix.com](mailto:service@vitamix.com), by telephone at 1-800-848-2649, or by facsimile at 440-235-3726  

* * *

| **UK & Ireland Privacy Policy**

Vitamix Corporation, Inc., a corporation incorporated under the laws of the State of Ohio, United States ("we") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our [terms of use](http://www.vitamix.co.uk/index.php?option=com_content&view=article&id=71) and any other documents referred to on it) explains our data processing practices and your options regarding the ways in which your personal data is used. 

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

By registering, placing an order, downloading information or entering our site (as defined below) you consent to the collection, use and transfer of your information under the terms of this policy.

**Information we may collect from you  
**We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Information that you provide by registering, ordering products or otherwise filling in forms on our sites [www.vitamix.co.uk ](http://www.vitamix.co.uk/)and [www.vitamix.ie ](http://www.vitamix.ie/). This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, purchasing products from our site, subscribing to our service including receiving recipes and news, downloading recipes and information posted on our site, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information in connection with or participation in any promotions or competitions sponsored, promoted or offered by us and/or any third party and information you provide when giving us feedback or completing profile forms and when you report a problem with our site or information we learn from your use of our service and your visits to our site.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of your orders, including, but not limited to your name, address, email address, telephone number and credit card number. 
  * Details of your visits to our site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, purchase information, weblogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access. 

**IP addresses and cookies  
**We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

  * To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.
  * To store information about your preferences and purchases, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests.
  * To speed up your searches.
  * To recognise you when you return to our site. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site and you may not be able to shop online. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

**Where we store your personal data  
**The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, amongst other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a username, login or password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this information confidential. We ask you not to share a username, login or password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**Uses made of the information  
**We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. 
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.
  * To contact you for your views on our services or products and to notify you about changes or developments to our service or products. 

We may also use your data, or permit selected third parties to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we or they may contact you about these by email, post or telephone.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you.

If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.

If you do not want us to use your data in these ways, or to pass your details on to third parties for marketing purposes, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data or contact us directly by post at 8615 Usher Road, Cleveland, Ohio 44138, Attn: Customer Service; by email at 

\n [service@vitamix.com](mailto:service@vitamix.com)

This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it 

; or by telephone to our Customer Service Department at 0845 8684566 (UK) or 0766709854 (Ireland). 

**Disclosure of your information  
**We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries.

We may also pass your information on to any successor or potential successor in title to our business and suppliers that process data on our behalf both in the United Kingdom and abroad. We may also use and disclose information in aggregate (so that no individual customers are identified) for marketing and strategic purposes.

**Your rights  
**You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by ticking certain boxes on any forms we use to collect your data or at any time by contacting us directly by post at 8615 Usher Road, Cleveland, Ohio 44138, Attn: Customer Service or by email at 

\n [service@vitamix.com](mailto:service@vitamix.com)

This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it 

.

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

**Access to information  
**The Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act) gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10.00 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

**Changes to our privacy policy  
**Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page.

**Contact  
**Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to 

\n [service@vitamix.com](mailto:service@vitamix.com)

This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it 

.
